Hopkins, Vivian C.; Papers ua902.003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- General Research, Writings, and Publication Materials, 1927-1979; 9.5 cubic ft.
  - Publications Concerning Emerson, 1953-1970; Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Publications Concerning Emerson Oversized Material, 1953-1970; Undated (Oversize 1)
  - "R.L.S. to W.E. Henley, Braemar, August, 1881", Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Recession - Great Lakes", Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "Rejected or Unrevised Material [on Satan]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "Remusat [on Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "Report on Speech Tests [Bacon]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - "Representative Men [Notes]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - "Research Fellowship Application", 1954; 1956; Undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Research Foundation, SUNY [on Francis Bacon]", 1957-1958; 1960-1961; 1963-1964; Undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - "Resuscitatio", Undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - "Review, 'Life of Banneker'", 1972 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - "Review of Blair Twain and Huck Finn", Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "Revue Germanique", Undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - "Rhymes of V.C.H. for Special Occasions", Undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Richard A. Yoder, Emerson's Poetry Article and Correspondence, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - "[Richard Lee] Francis - Emerson Cipher", 1972 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - "Road of Memory [Article and Draft]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - "[Robert] Frost - Rough Draft", Undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Robert Frost Notes and Articles (1 of 2), 1951-1976 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Robert Frost Notes and Articles (2 of 2), 1951-1976 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Robert Frost Notes and Articles Oversized Material, 1951-1976; Undated (Oversize 4)
  - "Robert Frost: Out Far and In Deep" by Vivian C. Hopkins (1 of 2), ca. 1960; Undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - "Robert Frost: Out Far and In Deep" by Vivian C. Hopkins (2 of 2), ca. 1960; Undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - "Rochester Material [Bacon Family Letters]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Roger Howson, "His Excellency a Trustee and Some Other Columbia Pieces", 1960 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - "Rough Draft Pt. 1 [Delia Bacon]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - "[Roy William] Cowden Memorial", 1962; Undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - "R[ussell] Sage Publicity", 1961; Undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - "RWE [Ralph Waldo Emerson] and Mythology", Undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Samuel L. Mitchill "Fishes of New York" Report with Correspondence Photocopies, Undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - "Samuel Taylor Shackford on Bacon", Undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - "Sarah Hershaw on Shakespeare", Undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - "Satan in Scripture and Literature", Undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Satan Manuscript Publication Correspondence, 1961-1966; 1968-1969; Undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Satan Notes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - "Satam Sheed and Ward 1952", Undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - "Schiller 'Marie Stuart'", Undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - "Schliegel and Hazlitt [Notes]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - "Science vs. Superstition", Undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - "Shaw - 'Fables [of the Ancients]'", Undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - "Slavery Outline", Undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - "Smedley [and Francis Bacon]", Undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - "Soldier of the 92nd Illinois" Serial Publication by Vivian C. Hopkins, Bulletin of the New York Public Library, Volume 73, Number 2, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - "Sowder on Emerson", Undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - "The Spirits and the Honorable John Worth Edmonds" Serial Publication by Vivian C. Hopkins, Bulletin of the New York Public Library, Volume 62, Number 10, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - "Speech Clinton and N.Y.S.", 1961; 1968; Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Spencer Amos Notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Spenser", 1935; Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Spetcher Clinton and Politics", Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Spires of Form" by Vivian C. Hopkins: Correspondence, Materials, and Notes, 1944; 1949-1951; 1953; Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "'Spires of Form' [Design and] Reviews", 1951; 1954; Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Spiritual Autobiography", 1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "[A Story for] Mei Mei", 1946; Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "Summary of Delia S. Lord", 1959; Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "Symposium Uticense", 1960; Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Syracuse U[niversity] Press on Clinton [Publication]", 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Talk on Libraries", Undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Tea for Ten", Undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - "'Temple of Wisdom,' Eames", 1959; Undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - "Terry Family", 1954 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "Theodore Bacon Papers", 1955; Undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Thomas Carlyle, "Sartor Resartus", Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Thomas Day Family Geneaology Notes, Undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - "Thoreau Publications", Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Thoreau Research Materials and Notes, 1958; 1962-1963; 1967-1970; Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Thoreau Research Materials and Notes Oversized Material, 1958; 1962-1963; 1967-1970; Undated (Oversize 2)
  - Times Magazine, "The Occult Revival", 1972 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Only cover and cover story is available online as an excerpt due to copyright. Complete item is available on request.
  - "Turners - Hall Keith", 1957; Undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - "Two Loves" Short Story, Undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - "Two Unpublished RWE [Ralph Waldo Emerson] Letters", 1960; Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - "Tyler 'Progress at Philosophy'", 1957; Undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Typed Copies of Bacon Family Letters at Yale, Undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Unidentified Index, Undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Unidentified Negatives, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Unidentified Notes and Writings (1 of 2), Undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Unidentified Notes and Writings (2 of 2), Undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified Short Stories, Poetry, and Plays with Drafts, Undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - The Unitarian Church of Albany Speaker Event, "The Church of the Mature Mind", 1952 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - "U[niversity of] Michigan Press Re. 'Bacon in America'", 1972 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - "University of Troy", Undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - "The Utopia of James Fenimore Cooper", Undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - "[Valcom to de Frashmen] Milt Gross", Undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Van der Kemp Erie Canal Oration Photostats from the New York Historical Society, Undated (Oversize 2)
  - "Van der Kemp - Servetus", 1959; Undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - "VCH Articles '35 - '36", 1935-1936; Undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - "Vindication of Thomas Jefferson" Photocopy with Annotations, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Vivian C. Hopkins Book Reviews, ca. 1960 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Vivian C. Hopkins Research Ledger, Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Walker on Clinton", 1963 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "Walt Whitman, Rveill", Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Walt Whitman Research Materials, 1955; 1959; 1961-1962; 1968; Undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Walt Whitman Research Materials Oversized Materials, 1955; 1959; 1961-1962; 1968; Undated (Oversize 2)
  - "Whicher Queries", 1958 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - White Cloud, "Sa-Ko-Ri-On-Nie-Ni", Undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - William A. Sessions Letter to Vivian C. Hopkins Concerning Bacon Research, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - William Murphy Letter and Notes [on Delia Bacon]", 1960; Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "Williams College Bacon", 1957; Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Wm. C. Bryant John W. Edmonds Address Typed Copy", Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Woman in Yellow" by Vivian C. Hopkins Short Story, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "The Women of Cambridge [Short Story]", Undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - "Word Count, T. Contents, Introductions, Etc., Bibliography [Satan Research]", Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "The Work of Art" by Vivian C. Hopkins Manuscript, Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "Wright Hearnshaw Wallace", Undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - "Yale Bacon Biographies", 1954 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - "Yale Material - Not Family", Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - "Yale University Press [and Art Gallery]", 1954; Undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Albany Gravel Company Records, 1908-1980; 1.09 cubic ft.
  This series contains the records of the Albany Gravel Company, also called Albany Gravel Co., up to its liquidation in 1980 to Valente Gravel. Vivian's father, John B. Hopkins, and brother, Richard W. Hopkins, both served as presidents of the company, with the latter becoming president after his father's death. Following the sudden death of John in 1972, Vivian, who was a member of the Board of Directors, started the liquidation of the company to Valente Gravel. The series includes meeting minutes, photographs, business correspondence, stock certificate ledgers property appraisals, licensing and inventory materials, and land contracts, such as that with Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute.
  - "About Highways" by Richard Hopkins, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accounts Charged Off Lists, 1927; 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albany Gravel Company Bookkeeper Position Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Amendment of Certificate of Incorporation, 1961; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Associated General Contractors of America Resolution Honoring Richard S. Hopkins, 1962 (Oversize 4)
  - Biography of Albany Gravel Co., 1974; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Boston Speech Labor and Contracts" by Richard Hopkins, 1937; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brainard Property Liquidation, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brainard Property Records, 1974; 1976-1978; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The Central Constructor Vol. 36 No. 11", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Charles W. Maxwell Obituary, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - City of Rensselaer Riverfront Land Liquidation Materials, 1974; 1976; 1978-1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Construction Management" Speech by Richard Hopkins to the American Society of Civil Engineers, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Contract: City of Rensselaer, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Contracting is a Business" Speech, Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Contracting Notebook, 1908 (Oversize 3)
  - Contracting Notebook, 1910; Undated (Oversize 3)
  - Contracting Notebook, 1937; Undated (Oversize 3)
  - Contracts: First Trust Company of Albany, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Contracts: William P. Rensselaer Estate Corporation, 1932; 1938; 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1918; 1931; 1938; 1945; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence About City of Rensselaer Maps, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: American Steel and Wire Company, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Barker and Wheeler Engineers, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Frank Cooney Construction Cost, 1933; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Neil Hellman and Town House Company, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Price Increase, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Property Estimation, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Steiner and Steiner About the Death of John Hopkins, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: William P. Van Rensselaer Estate Corporation, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: William W. Farley, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Day Labor and Contract Workers Materials, 1933; 1935-1937; Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Explosives Licensing Forms, 1946-1948; 1950; 1954; Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Father's Speech: Relation Between Engineer and Contractor", Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Finances", 1923-1975; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Glens Falls Materials, 1932; 1941-1943; Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "The Highway Contractor and Road Builder Vol. IV No. 4", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Inventory Lists, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "John B. Hopkins Town of East Greenbush Field Notes", 1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Liquidation Finance Forms and Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Lease: A.E. Ottaviano, Inc., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Lease: Herzog and Hopkins, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Low Bidder Articles", 1927-1928; 1931-1932; 1958; 1976; Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Meeting Minutes (1 of 2), 1950-1978; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Minutes (2 of 2), 1950-1978; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Nassau Property Estimates, 1973; 1976-1978; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "New York State Department of Highways [Contract] Estimate Forms with R[ichard] Hopkins", 1910 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - NYU Speeches by Richard Hopkins, 1934; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pettingill v. Albany Gravel Co., 1932 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photograph of Gravel Pit, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Photograph (Copy) of Richard S. Hopkins, 1977; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Photograph of Richard S. Hopkins", Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Albany Gravel Co., 1962; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Property Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Proposed Sale of Albany Gravel Company to [Joseph] Valente", 1975; 1978; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Reno Green Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute Earthwork Sheets Materials, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute Lease Renewal Correspondence and Materials, 1971-1975; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute Payments, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Richard Hopkins, Contractor" Draft and Manuscript, Edited by Vivian C. Hopkins, Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Richard Hopkins Court of Appeals, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Sales Tax Bureau Credit Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "Specifications and Contract for 2nd Annual Banquet Employees Division No. 6, N.Y. State Dept. of H[igh]ways", 1912 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - State of New York Act Print. 5494 Intro. 4877 Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Stock and Transfer Ledger", 1964-1973; Undated (Oversize 3)
  - "Stock and Transfer Ledger" Loose Materials, 1964-1973; Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "[Stock] Certificates Ledger (1 of 2)", 1923-1974; Undated (Oversize 3)
  - "Stock Certificates Ledger (2 of 2)", 1923-1974; Undated (Oversize 3)
  - "[Stock] Certificates Ledger (1 of 2)" Loose Materials, 1923-1974; Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "Stock Certificates Ledger (2 of 2)" Loose Materials, 1923-1974; Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "Taxes: Nassau and Brainard", 1966; 1977-1979; Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Transferring Rensselaer River Front Site to Valente Gravel Inc.", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Union Agreement Forms, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 27)